<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chicagoland's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Gary Jacklin, a top Real Estate Agent in Chicagoland, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 09:41:59 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 09:41:59 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You on Track With Your Goals?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JN53auaUx0o?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;This is your wake-up call about reaching your 2021 business goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m apologizing ahead of time because I’m going to give you a kick in the teeth you may need. Today I’m discussing your 2021 goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to take a look at your main goal and &lt;strong&gt;ask yourself, “Am I on track to achieve my goal by the end of the year?”&lt;/strong&gt; You only have about four months left to achieve your goal, so if you’re not on track to reach it, you aren’t spending enough time in the four dollar-producing activities of listing, selling, negotiating, and prospecting. If you’re currently thinking to yourself, “I do this full time, but it’s such a wacky market!” I have a couple of questions you should ask yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you uploading, downloading, and creating? You’re not going to make money doing those things because they’re not dollar-productive activities. How much time are you spending with buyers? &lt;strong&gt;You should be focusing on growing your career, which means working with listings and sellers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You only have about four months left to achieve your goal.%20http://localhost:4000/are-you-on-track-with-your-goals.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You only have about four months left to achieve your goal.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need voice to voice to get a face to face appointment. You want to target sellers because on average, one buyer will take up 32 hours of your time, while a seller will only take up eight. We’ve discussed only working with qualified buyers in the past, and they’re those who also have a home to sell. If you’re focused on speaking with sellers every day, the majority of them will also buy a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal today was to rattle your cage, get you back on track, and help you hit your goal. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re not on track to reach your goal by the end of 2021, we need to talk.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://join.gochicagolandhomes.com/ask/fcaee647b264e3da187d14e0fd4647b1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Download this free document&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that will help you develop a business plan and stay on track. Then call, text, or email me. I’d be glad to share what we do here at RE/MAX Action and how you can get results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-on-track-with-your-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-on-track-with-your-goals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 3 Fundamentals for a Successful Real Estate Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UiNwduT3rCY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;These three fundamentals can help you find success in your real estate business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three fundamentals that can help guarantee your success as a real estate agent. If you follow and build upon these foundations, you can ensure that your business thrives. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s what you need to do:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Build it first:&lt;/strong&gt; Anything that is built must first be envisioned, but you have to come up with a plan to make it happen. You need to have a written business plan that will help you accomplish your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Be intentional:&lt;/strong&gt; Sticking to the plan means adhering to a schedule. You need to block out time to get things done, and you need to be fully present in your activities. You have your family life and your spiritual life, and now you need your business life. When you’re working, remove distractions and focus on growing your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Focus on the major things:&lt;/strong&gt; In sales, you can’t get bogged down in minor processes—you need to put your energy into the things that truly matter. It can be easy to “prepare to prepare” for minor things like updating databases or uploading Facebook posts. The major things come from instances where you are “in the presence of” clients, prospects, and others who make you revenue. Look at your schedule, see where you spend your time, and make sure you’re using the majority of it in the presence of clients. Delegate the minor things to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to go deeper into these concepts, or if you’d like to learn more about growing your business, feel free to reach out to me. If you’re looking for a place to start, &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.gochicagolandhomes.com/ask/58242ecbeb328b03b00891a17fab7920&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;click here for a free download&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I look forward to helping you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-3-fundamentals-for-a-successful-real-estate-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-3-fundamentals-for-a-successful-real-estate-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips for Agents With Limited Time or Money</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Sqj0TqGIPF0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here are my tips on dealing with limited time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no denying it: Every real estate agent out there struggles with two major things. Either they don’t have enough money or they don’t have enough time. Here are some practical steps to address both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Focusing on listings instead of buyers will save you time&lt;/strong&gt;. If you’re focused on buyers, you’re spending on average at least 32 hours per buyer. If you focus on listings, you’re doing four times as much within the same amount of time. It takes an average of eight hours to work with a typical seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Only work with qualified buyers and sellers&lt;/strong&gt;. When I go on a listing appointment, the best listing I could have is a seller that wants to buy. That’s not to say that we don’t have our challenges. I’ve talked in the past about what we can do to help that seller deal with the fear of not finding the right house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Do what others are unwilling to do&lt;/strong&gt;. There’s a reason why 10% of the agents do 90% of the business. If you’re not where you want to be production-wise or you’re spending too much time doing the number of transactions that you’re doing, then you need to be willing to do what the others aren’t willing to do and be proactive. Go back to the fundamentals, have a conversation face-to-face, and go on listing appointments. Send out about 15 to 20 simple tests to your database every day. Ask them if they know what’s going on in the market and if they’re at all curious as to what their home’s value is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Your focus should always be on listings.%20http://localhost:4000/3-tips-for-agents-with-limited-time-or-money.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Your focus should always be on listings.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go back to your past clients and text them, ask if they’re aware of what their property value is right now, then do a market analysis and get in front of them. This opens the conversation, but we’re always focused on the listing. When we’re focused on their listing, their fear is going to be that they can’t find a home. However, since you’re being proactive and doing what others won’t do, which is door-knocking and cold calling, you can find a home for them. You’ll be finding other listings in the meantime. Your focus should always be on listings. Here is a &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://join.gochicagolandhomes.com/ask/555fae405f781c5136a61a284b09d037&quot;&gt;free download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; with some slides to help you on your listing appointment and with buyers to show them why now is the very best time to buy and sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to email, call, or text me. If you’d like a written business plan on how to move forward and really implement these strategies, I’d be happy to meet with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-tips-for-agents-with-limited-time-or-money.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-tips-for-agents-with-limited-time-or-money.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Help Sellers Overcome Fears of Homelessness</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jfWq3mouhcQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Today I’m sharing advice on how you can help overcome a client’s selling fears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m talking about how to overcome the No. 1 objection that sellers have about listing their homes right now. Sellers are saying, “I’m not going to list my house because I’m afraid I won’t find a home to purchase.” So how do we overcome their fear of homelessness?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Discuss everything thoroughly with the client&lt;/strong&gt;. We go into this in a very methodical way. We have our plan and share that with the client so they can have confidence in us that by implementing all of these strategies as part of our marketing plan, we’ll find them a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Organize a rent-back agreement&lt;/strong&gt;. Possession is different than closing, so if we buy some time by delaying the closing, it can be risky. I’d rather work with possession. In multiple-offer situations, work with the offer that will do an extended possession where the seller can rent back at the buyer’s price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you're on that listing appointment, do what the other agents are unwilling to do.%20http://localhost:4000/help-sellers-overcome-fears-of-homelessness.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“When you’re on that listing appointment, do what the other agents are unwilling to do.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Leverage your time to find listings for your clients&lt;/strong&gt;. When sellers won’t list because they can’t find a home to buy, that’s the perfect opportunity for the specific buyer dialogue. That’s strategy! If you are unaware of what that is, &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://join.gochicagolandhomes.com/ask/0f71d6291fda676980a5ebfe3bee64c6&quot;&gt;click here to download the specific buyer script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. Now we need to go out to the marketplace the seller told you they like. Now you’re leveraging your time to find the perfect home for that particular seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, you’re going to find other listings and other people that are moving. That’s how you fill your pipeline listings in the future. By doing this, you will also find a home for another client. This becomes part of your arsenal of marketing plans when you’re working with the seller. When you’re on that listing appointment, do what the other agents are unwilling to do. Make phone calls and knock on doors to find listings for your particular buyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like more specifics on exactly how to go about doing that, call, text, or email me. I’d be happy to answer any questions for you. Have a great day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/help-sellers-overcome-fears-of-homelessness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/help-sellers-overcome-fears-of-homelessness.html</guid>
        
        <category>Listing Presentation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 5 Reasons Home Sellers Want to List</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Uwt8tnp6eWE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;These are the five main reasons why people choose to sell their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why homeowners don’t want to sell their homes, but &lt;strong&gt;there are five specific reasons why most of them do want to sell:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Their home no longer meets their needs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They want to make a profit in the current market.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They want a smaller house with less work.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They want to live closer to friends and family.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They want different features and amenities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To know what these sellers are thinking, you need to be their trusted advisor. You have a gold mine in your phone, but are you mining it? Are you calling the people in your database? If you’re not, start now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you at least touch base with them, because if they’re thinking about moving, they’re thinking about one of the five items in the list I mentioned above. &lt;strong&gt;Understand, ask questions, and try to discover where they’re at as a homeowner&lt;/strong&gt;. Most agents will not do that simple task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You have a gold mine in your phone, but are you mining it?%20http://localhost:4000/the-5-reasons-home-sellers-want-to-list.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You have a gold mine in your phone, but are you mining it?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for my next video where I’ll cover the biggest objections from home sellers, aka “What’s holding them back?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about prospecting, scripts, or anything else related to the real estate business, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-5-reasons-home-sellers-want-to-list.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-5-reasons-home-sellers-want-to-list.html</guid>
        
        <category>Listing Presentation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Overcome the 3 Biggest Challenges in Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g1znhALnYro?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Here’s a look into the three biggest issues real estate agents face daily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the biggest challenges facing agents today, there are three that come to mind right away. I’m going to go through each of them and show you how to overcome them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Time.&lt;/strong&gt; We all have the same 24 hours in the day, but why are some of us more productive than others? One of the big factors is learning to say “no.” It’s not that you don’t want to help somebody out, but it can often get you off track. If it’s not going to interrupt your focus, by all means, help. However, sometimes you just need to say, “I’d love to, but I can’t right now.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping your focus is also important. Prioritize specific activities for specific periods of the day. You should be spending two hours prospecting every day and pre-scheduling your appointments. The most dollar-productive times are evenings and weekends. Prioritize them in this order: Listings → buyer appointments → prospecting time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Money.&lt;/strong&gt; This is critical to our business and success. You are the CEO of your business as a real estate agent. Are you holding your money accountable? You need to know why you’re paying for something, what you’re getting back from the money you are spending, and whether or not you truly need to purchase something based on your budget. Everyone is going to try to sell you the “easy” button, but it doesn’t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s important to leverage the admin staff on your team.%20http://localhost:4000/overcome-the-3-biggest-challenges-in-real-estate.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s important to leverage the admin staff on your team.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. People.&lt;/strong&gt; You have a team whether you realize it or not. It might just be your broker. You need leadership to help you sustain and grow your business. Do you have a mentor you trust? A coach that holds you accountable? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also want to have access to training to master the basic skills so you can become a more profitable agent. Your admin staff is important as well. Have you really leveraged this staff? If you’re doing it all yourself, you’re just an unpaid secretary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These questions barely scratch the surface of what you need to be a successful real estate agent.&lt;/strong&gt; At RE/MAX Action, we’re focused on you working smarter, not harder. I have a step-by-step plan that I’d love to share with you; just reach out to me, and I’ll send you a copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions for me about the real estate business, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email today. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/overcome-the-3-biggest-challenges-in-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/overcome-the-3-biggest-challenges-in-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 3 Steps to Follow When Hiring an Assistant</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UOV9asmhb7E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;These are the steps you need to follow to make sure you hire a great assistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; href=&quot;https://joinrma.com/are-you-hiring-an-assistant.html&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, I talked about how to navigate the process of hiring an assistant. Afterward, I had a lot of people reaching out to me and asking for more information about this process, so I thought it’d be helpful to provide an overview of the three key steps to follow. Here’s what you should do when hiring an assistant for your real estate business:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Understand which vital activities are most relevant&lt;/strong&gt;. There are vital tasks that must be done in a real estate business, but not all of them are relevant to you as an agent. You want to be focused on the dollar-productive activities and leave the behind-the-scenes work to your assistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Know the strengths and weaknesses of the position&lt;/strong&gt;. After you know what your assistant will focus on, you need to figure out what strengths they’ll need to have. Will your assistant be doing a lot of paperwork, for example? In that case, you want someone who’s very detail-oriented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Know how their characteristics align with the position&lt;/strong&gt;. A DiSC assessment can be incredibly helpful when going through potential candidates and making sure their strengths align with what you’re looking for. For example, you may want someone who’s more cautious or someone who’s very compassionate. The DiSC assessment can help you discover these traits in candidates before choosing who to hire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d be happy to share the resources I use with you. If you have any questions about hiring an assistant or would like more information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-3-steps-to-follow-when-hiring-an-assistant.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-3-steps-to-follow-when-hiring-an-assistant.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Easily Manage Multiple Offers on Your Listings</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/v-GR2PGTVKc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;There are some simple ways to organize multiple offers successfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re dealing with different listings that have multiple offers, things can quickly get out of control and lead to a lot of confusion. That’s why it’s important to keep everything organized by including three key things in your multiple offer summary worksheet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, you obviously want to include the contact information for the listing, such as the address, seller’s name, etc. &lt;strong&gt;Next, you want to list all of the information regarding the contract—using a spreadsheet can help out a lot with this.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The names of buyers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Their agents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The offering price&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seller credits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Purchase price&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Escalation clauses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Earnest money&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Down payment percentages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Types of loans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lenders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Closing dates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inspections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Concessions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Additional comments and information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You should also create a columned list of all the offers made, as well as their terms.&lt;/strong&gt; While this is great for personal reference, it’s also something you can share with your sellers when you’re discussing offers. It helps further when coming up with counter offers, as there’s far more to consider than just the price. You’ll want to be able to easily look at the terms, how much they’re putting down, and other information mentioned in the list above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take the time to organize your listings in these ways, you’ll find the process of managing multiple offers becomes much, much easier. If you have any questions or would like more information, always feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-easily-manage-multiple-offers-on-your-listings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-easily-manage-multiple-offers-on-your-listings.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Hiring an Assistant?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tGfCjpclvUc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center style=&quot;font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how to make your first hiring decision a good one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you want to grow your production and get to the next level, hiring an assistant is a must. As I’ve touched on in previous videos, it’s vital that agents stay focused on those core dollar-productive activities. Everything that’s not vital to a transaction is still relevant, but it should be handled by someone else that you can trust. What’s the process that drives your business forward? What do you need to know, do, and have to hire the right person and train them adequately on that process?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many agents think that hiring someone just because they’ve been in real estate before is a good call. Truth be told, experience moving through the revolving door of real estate is no reason to hire someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ve put together a free, downloadable guide designed to help you hire the ideal assistant&lt;/strong&gt;. Just give me a call, text, or email and I’ll get that right out to you. I’d also be more than happy to answer any other questions on how to leverage your business in a very effective and efficient way. Let’s have a conversation soon; today is a perfect time to start breaking through to that next level!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-hiring-an-assistant.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/are-you-hiring-an-assistant.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 4 Steps to Getting Listings Now</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/c5LqbaTeeh8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center style=&quot;font-size: 18px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;These four steps will help you get more listings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There’s an adage in the real estate business: If you’re not busy, get yourself busy. In other words, if you don’t have enough listings, then you need to get out there and find them. Today I’ll share the four steps it takes to get more listings quickly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Use your phone’s contact records&lt;/strong&gt;. When was the last time you stopped playing with your CRM and actually called these contacts? Agents often have anywhere from 800 to 3,000 contacts on their phones.  You can download these contacts to your desktop and call them from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Call to check in and see what’s happening&lt;/strong&gt;. Many people are frustrated right now due to being constricted to their homes, and they want to move. Our low inventory is often what holds them back from selling. If there aren’t enough listings, you need to get out there and find them. Reach out to me for a script you can use to find listings for sellers who will need to buy once they’ve listed their homes. You can use it to create a personal listing network of those people who are willing to show their homes to specific buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Once you’ve made 50 to 60 calls, I bet you’ll be very busy listing and selling homes.%20http://localhost:4000/the-4-steps-to-getting-listings-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Once you’ve made 50 to 60 calls, I bet you’ll be very busy listing and selling homes.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Start filling your pipeline&lt;/strong&gt;. Fill your pipeline with your inventory of people who may move when they find something to buy first. This will give you listings. In the meantime, it will also help you find other potential sellers who may want to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Just do it&lt;/strong&gt;. Put these strategies into action. Once you’ve made 50 to 60 calls, I bet you’ll be very busy listing and selling homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like more information about our specific buyer strategy, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:6306382600&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;uploads/Button - 345.png&quot; width=&quot;345&quot; height=&quot;75&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-4-steps-to-getting-listings-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-4-steps-to-getting-listings-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
